Guide to the Gay Cable Network Archives, 1982-2001 MSS.231
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series X: Gay USA
  - 1994 Vol. XII
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 23 [Air date: 6/9/1994], June 1994; ID: 231.0405 (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0405)
      1. News Notes: Protests at Out Day at Disney World. Late-breaking announcement: William Andrews, chair of the HIV/AIDS Advisory Council makes homophobic remarks. Viewers are encouraged to call Carol Gressor and Chancellor Ramon Cortines to demand Andrews' resignation.
      2. March in Queens is shown. John Won, grand marshal, is interviewed, as is Alan Hevesi, Jeanne Manford of PFLAG, Candice Boyce, Karen Burstein, Ruth Messinger, Howard Cruse, Danny Dromm, Ron Gold, Terry van Dyke, Ray Dries, Paul O'Dwyer, Matt Foreman.
      3. Vivian Shapiro and Isabel Kuschner of the Legacy Foundation are interviewed.
      4. Joe Kennedy, author of The Summer of 77: The Last Hurrah of the Gay Activist Alliance.
      5. At the Hetrick Martin Institute, 8th Annual Emory Hetrick Awards. Frances Kunreuther, Herb Cohen, Luis Reyes, and the recipients, Youth of Massachusetts are interviewed.
      6. Lavender Health: Part 3. Nathan Kerr, Jim Jones, Jacinto Jorge, Jerome Zorrilla, Gay Games IV athletes, are interviewed.
      7. Naming Names: WWOR uses unrelated pride parade footage during a serious piece on the gay rights bill. Viewers are encouraged to write to Will Right of WWOR.
      8. A Stonewall update is replaced with footage from a press conference at the Gay and Lesbian Community Center, discussing the route of the Stonewall 25 march. Franklin G. Fry, BC Craig, and Pat Norman speak. The Giuliani administration is trying to block off and reroute the march and constantly changes their minds on important aspects of the Stonewall 25 events.
      9. Gay Games IV update with Robert McCarthy and Kile Ozier
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 24 [Air date: 6/16/1994], June 1994; ID: 231.0406 (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0406)
      1. News Notes: Vermont grants domestic partnership benefits to gays and lesbians. Mary Cummins quits. John Boswell's book reveals gay marriages in the middle ages. Liza Minelli is barred by Giuliani from appearing at the Stonewall 25 rally. The International Dyke March is announced.
      2. New York Public Library hosts Becoming Visible: The Legacy of Stonewall. The exhibit is shown, as curators show photographs.
      3. John Won and Adamo of the Riot Conference for Youth at Hunter College are interviewed.
      4. AMFAR Benefit, interview with Mathilde Krim.
      5. Kate Bornstein, author and playwright, known for Virtually Yours, is interviewed. A clip of her show is shown.
      6. Lavender Health: Dr. Alberto Avendano of the National Association of People With AIDS is interviewed.
      COMMERCIAL: Celebration of Uncommon Women
      7. Naming Names: James B. Stewart's article in The New Yorker on discrimination against gays in the workplace is praised by GLAAD, as is the cover of two gay men marrying. Viewers are encouraged to write to Tina Brown, editor-in-chief of the New Yorker.
      8. Larry Flick and Pefidia of Lifebeat are interviewed.
      COMMERCIAL: Alan Pratt Announces the Moment of Silence
      9. Lou Maletta interviews Y'all, a group of gay country singers. The group performs.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 25 [Air date: 6/23/1994], June 1994; ID: 231.0407 (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0407)
      COMMERCIAL: AmFAR with Elizabeth Taylor
      1. News Notes: Presbyterians bans acknowledgement of gay unions. The passing of Bruce Mailman is announced. Milton Berle is appearing in a drag show. The Human Rights Commission is in threat of shutting down.
      2. Gay and Lesbian Community Center's Garden Party. Mark Green, John Dowd, Marcie Kahn, Ruth Messinger, Father Lynch interviewed. Richard Burns, Kate Clinton speak.
      3. Kate Clinton is interviewed by Deborah Barsha. Some of Kate Clinton's stand-up is shown.
      COMMERCIAL: Public Awareness Project
      4. The opening ceremony of Gay Games IV is shown. Rudy Giuliani speaks, and a sizable portion of the crowd boos and heckles him. Lengthy march of each participating country. The torch-lighting is shown, as is a massive fireworks display.
      COMMERCIAL: Help Stop the Violence
      5. Naming Names: American Airlines trains employees in non-discrimination. Viewers are encouraged to write to American Airlines.
      6. At the Tavern on the Green, Jay Hill and Brent Nicholson-Earl introduce the games. The daughter of Tom Wadell, Jessica Waddell Lowenstein is interviewed.
      7. Judy Tenuta performs.
      COMMERCIAL: ADS AGAINST AIDS
      8. After the credits, Lou Maletta and two others stand near the bleachers of Gay Games IV and are going to make an announcement before the tape cuts out.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 26 [Air date: 6/30/1994], June 1994; ID: 231.0408A (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0408A)
      1. News Notes: Lee Sharmat won a silver and bronze medal in the Gay Games. Sharon Bottoms wins appeal, then has her son taken away by grandmother. Bill Andrews proposes ban of GMHC. Colors Magazine posts a fake photo of Ronald Reagan with AIDS. Hawaiin legislature bans same sex marriage. Mike McAlary sued by woman who was raped in Prospect Park.
      2. Lee Sharmat and Andy Humm introduce footage of the Stonewall march. Gay Activist Alliance marches. Sharmat interviews a few of the marchers, among them Tom Duane. The march is shown arriving in Central Park, and performances are shown. Toni James is interviewed. The Stonewall veterans get on stage. Liza Minelli and others speak.
      3. Lavender Health: Footage of Joycelyn Elders, US Surgeon General, and her speech about healthcare, safe sex, and gay and lesbian health at the National Lesbian and Gay Health Foundation.
      COMMERCIAL: WHY NOT LOVE?
      4. Naming Names: City officials drastically undercount Stonewall 25 participants. CNN quotes the city officials verbatim. Viewers are encouraged to write Roger Bahre at CNN.
      5. The closing ceremony at Yankee Stadium is shown. Some of the athletes and participants are interviewed, although none are named. Performances are shown. Fireworks are shown over the credits.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 27 [Air date: 7/7/1994], July 1994; ID: 231.0409 (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0409)
      1. News Notes: David Axelrod's death is covered. More organizations are calling for boycott of Florida Orange Juice due to Rush Limbaugh. Giuliani cuts service workers. Stonewall 25 is $300,000 in debt. Michael J. Petrides, who fought against condom distribution and the Children of the Rainbow coalition, dies.
      2. Lee Sharmat announces eleven athletes have had to return their medals after testing positive for steroids. Dan Meyers reports from the Abe Stark Arena for the men's and pair's ice skating competition. Linda Carney and Laura Moore perform and are interviewed. Mark Heard and Jean Pierre-Martin perform and are interviewed. Matthew Hall performs.
      3. There are now 156 openly lesbian and gays holding office. Paul Richards and Virginia Appuzo speak at the Victory Fund party. Dick Dadey and Jon David Nalley are interviewed.
      4. Andy Humm and Joe Lovett announce the broadcast of In a New Light.
      5. Lavender Health: Part two. Footage of Joycelyn Elders, US Surgeon General, and her speech about healthcare, safe sex, and gay and lesbian health at the National Lesbian and Gay Health Foundation.
      6. Naming Names: Time Magazine almost completely ignores Stonewall 25 apart from a one-sentence mention that the organization is in debt. Viewers are encouraged to write to Time Magazine to demand better coverage.
      7. The Museum of Television and Radio (now the Paley Center) hosts John Scagliotti, executive prouder of In the Life speaks. Barbara Raab, producer for Dateline NBC, David Sloan, a producer for 20/20, and Ann Northrop are interviewed.
      8. Madeline D'Anthony of the Adult Industry Trade Association is interviewed about a restrictive new law. The number of the Adult Industry Trade Association is shown.
      9. Footage of Debi Thomas skating is shown over the credits.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 28 [Air date: 7/14/1994], July 1994; ID: 231.0410 (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0410)
      1. News Notes: 30 anti-gay assaults occur during Gay Games and Stonewall 25, which the city is denying happened. Giuliani's office number is displayed. Christine Gebby resigns. Three more athletes disqualified after using steroids during Gay Games. Dick Sargent's death is announced. Brett Easton Ellis' sexuality is questioned. Viewers are warned against going to the Caiman Islands.
      2. Karen Burstein, candidate for New York State Attorney General is interviewed.
      3. Vernal Scott introduces regular reports from England. A pride march is shown in London.
      4. California football finalist game shown. Team LA vs LA Quakes. Jim Buzinski of Team LA, Lynn Lewis of Team NY interviewed.
      5. Lavender Health: Ken Togo, who opened the first clinic for gay men and lesbians in Japan, and is an acclaimed LBGT figure there, is interviewed. Togo's stage performance is shown.
      6. Special Edition of Naming Names, The GLAAD Report Card on Stonewall 25, which covers the best and worst coverage of Gay Games IV and Stonewall 25. Top honors go to New York Newsday, The New York Times, CBS Evening News, News 4 NY, and New York 1. Dunce caps go to The New York Post, Sports Illustrated, ABC News, Channel 5 News at 10, and Good Day New York.
      7. The Lambda Update: Beatrice Dohrn introduces the broadcast. Lou Maletta interviews Evan Wolfson about the same sex equal rights case in Hawaii. Patrick Lagon and Joe Mellio, plaintiffs in the case, are interviewed as well. Nina Baehr and Genora Dancel, Barbara Warkas and Carol Lam are interviewed as well.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 29 [Air date: 7/21/1994], July 1994; ID: 231.0411 (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0411)
      NOTES: New set for opening segment.
      1. News Notes: Clinton wants Tracy Thorne thrown out of NAVY. Olympic committee considering moving volleyball game from outside of Cobb County. Boy Scouts lose funding from United Way. Barry Goldwater endorses gay rights. Viewers are encouraged to call the NYC School Chancellor to demand that William Andrews be fired after remarks that gays were "coming for your children". Gay book store in Cincinnati is raided by police for carrying a copy of "Salo: 120 Days of Sodom". A demonstration against George Pataki is announced.
      2. Arnie Kantrowitz of the Gay Activists Alliance speaks.
      3. Gay Games IV coverage: David Mitchell covers martial arts. Jesse Garcia covers water polo finals. Ed Dixon covers bowling.
      4. Lavender Health: Tuberculosis short film. Dr. Thomas Freeden, director of Tuberculosis Control is interviewed.
      5. Naming Names: The Tonight Show features its first openly gay comedian, Bob Smith. Viewers are encouraged to write to Bill Royce, co-producer of The Tonight Show.
      6. Interview with Particia Nell Warren, author of Harlan's Race.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 30 [Air date: 7/28/1994], July 1994; ID: 231.0412 (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0412)
      1. News Notes: Rush Limbaugh fired as Florida Citrus spokesman. Military banned from recruiting at University of Connecticut Law School. Wigstock in danger of not happening. Cardinal O'Connor announces he will close every Catholic hospital in the city if abortion becomes part of national health care reform. Filming is beginning on The Celluloid Closet. 'The Ramrod Killer' is trying to get out of psychiatric care. Harvey Firestein headlines CBS sitcom. Sue Simmons reveals accidentally that she is a lesbian.
      2. At the Sheraton New York, multi-million dollar fundraiser for George Pataki, who says he is against gay rights. Ann Northrup and Senator Al D'Amato interviewed. George Pataki speaks to reporters, when Andy Humm tries to ask a question, an activist shouts "Pataki is a bigot!". Rudy Washington, commissioner, Howard Koeppel (a gay Republican), and Betsy McCaughey are interviewed. Caroline Quartararo, Pataki's press secretary is interviewed and angrily demands Humm turn the camera off.
      3. London's memorial quilt and The Names Project UK is covered. Vernal Scott reports from London and tours the quilt and some of the exhibits around it.
      4. Lavender Health: Harm reduction on a day to day basis. Howard Josepher speaks. Donna La Loma,
      5. Larry Kramer is interviewed.
      6. Naming Names: Woodstock 94 hosts Shabba Ranks, who has made homophobic statements. Viewers are encouraged to write to Michael Lang of Woodstock Ventures to get Ranks pulled.
      7. Lambda Update: Kevin Cathcart introduces Suzanne B. Goldberg, discussing anti-gay initiatives.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 31 [Air date: 8/4/1994], August 1994; ID: 231.0413 (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0413)
      1. News Notes: Congress will have a hearing on work discrimination against gays and lesbians. Cobb County is covered in an article in the New York Times, 'A Suburban Eden Where the Right Rules'. Susan Sarandon endorses Tom Duane. Serial killer Gary Ray Bowles is sought in the south. Gay Games needs money to cover its loss. Norma McCorvey comes out.
      2. Matt Foreman of the Anti-Violence Project is interviewed and holds a town meeting on police misconduct and abuse, and the Rueben Diaz controversy. Edward Silver, Ruth Messigner, and Deborah Glick speak.
      3. Lavender Health: Closing ceremony of Gay Games IV at Yankee Stadium with Dan Myers. Edna Spring, Jose Badue, Jim Frawley, Reggie Snowdon, and Gwinn Leggis interviewed.
      4. Angelica Rovira and Mark E. Seitelman are interviewed. Rovira The audio on this segment is very bad at the start of the interview. Rovira claims she was assaulted by Luis Solard (sp?) of the school board.
      5. GLAAD Media Alert (formerly Naming Names): American Express advertises to gay and lesbians. Viewers are encouraged to write to Harvey Golub of American Express. An update states that the Olympic committee has pulled the volleyball event from Cobb County.
      6. Lee Sharmat interviews Judy Nelson, host of In the Life.
      7. Footage from the Powerlifting event of Gay Games IV. Tom Tudesco is interviewed.
      COMMERCIAL: Teleconference from The International AIDS Conference
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 32 [Air date: 8/11/1994], August 1994; ID: 231.0414 (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0414)
      1. News Notes: Because Andy Humm had knee surgery, News Notes is held from Humm's apartment bed. Patsy Flemming is interim AIDS czar. Greenburg, New York is considering benefits for gay and lesbian couples. Tom Duane is having a fundraiser. A broadcast about a botched 911 response from NY1 featuring Matt Foreman and Tom Duane is shown. GLAAD protests anti-gay t-shirts being sold on the Jersey Shore, with the support of the New Jersey governor. Liam Neeson is considered for the lead in an Oscar Wilde biopic by Mike Nichols.
      2. International AIDS Conference in Yokohama, Japan. A satellite feed from Japan of a roundtable conference is shown, taped off of a monitor with Closed Captioning turned on (the audience can be heard murmuring and coughing). Michael Saag is the only one identified by text. Dale Hogan provides an outro and interviews Brian Jankowsi of the Treatment Action Group.
      3. Lou Maletta interviews Richard Jones, intern on The Howard Stern Show, who is openly gay.
      COMMERCIAL: Speak to the Senate (a recent senate decision overwhelmingly ruled against 'gay education' in schools)
      4. Lavender Health: The US House and Senate pass a bill called the Elementary and Secondary Act, which featured an amendment introduced by Bob Smith and Jesse Helms prohibiting school districts from providing counseling to gay students or distributing material that deals with gay and lesbian issues, or making referrals to gay and lesbian organizations. From the Harvey Milk School, Maisha Uzuri James is interviewed.
      5. GLAAD Media Alert: Willard Scott endorses Cracker Barrel on The Today Show. Viewers are encouraged to write to The Today Show and tell them to stop endorsing Cracker Barrel.
      6. Lambda Update: Beatrice Dohrn discusses gays in the military. Footage from Donahue is shown.
      7. Andy Humm tries to unravel the bandage on his knee while the credits roll.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 33 [Air date: 8/18/1994], August 1994; ID: 231.0415 (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0415)
      1. News Notes: George Pataki gets a '100% approval rating' from Pat Robertson. Protests in Huntsville, Alabama over the Metropolitan Community Church, which accepts gays and lesbians as parishioners. Andrew Crispo leaves info on phone sex lines. Eve's Garden celebrates 25th anniversary. Under Giuliani, gay interest and human rights groups are being gutted. Gabriel Rotello attacks Christopher Lynn for endorsing Rueben Diaz. Cincinnati anti-gay measure is thrown out. The Catholic Church condemns the UN for endorsing condoms and sexual health.
      2. Woodstock 94 is covered. Lou Maletta interviews attendees. Some of Nine Inch Nails' concert is briefly shown.
      3. Highlights from GCN's debate with Jerry Nadler and Tom Duane. Its announced that the full 1-hour debate will appear on Out on Wednesdays, August 25th at 11pm.
      4. Lavender Health: Benjamin A Mojica of STD Control is interviewed.
      5. GLAAD Media Alert: The Helms/Smith sponsored amendment which will cut funds to schools that 'advance the homosexual lifestyle' is covered. Viewers are encouraged to write to their congressmen; Sen Al D'amato for NY.
      6. Deborah Barsha in Newark, NY on the set of The Incredibly True Adventure of Two Girls in Love. Maria Maggenti, Dolly Hall, Lori E. Seid, and Mark Huisman are interviewed.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 34 [Air date: 8/25/1994], August 1994; ID: 231.0416 (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0416)
      1. News Notes: Urban Fitness is launched. A study reveals 20% of adults have gay impulses. In Tacoma, WA, the home of three gay roommates is targeted by vandals. Mayor Joseph Maranin in Connecticut wants to kill AIDS services. University of Wisconsin decides against domestic partner benefits. Nelson Thacker, who killed a gay man in Salt Lake City has his sentence reduced. Sierra Club offers straight and gay trips. Nebraska lesbian fighting to keep custody of son. Sharon Bottoms trying to get hearing in custody case. The New York Times runs a story on how hard of a sell gay movies are. Wigstock finds a host.
      2. The Morning Party. Jeff Richardson, and Nora Burns interviewed.
      3. Tom Duane interviewed. Duane and Ann Northrop speak.
      5. GLAAD Media Alert: The Sony Video 1 board in Times Square refuses to run a gay PSA called 'Why not love?' The spot is shown. Viewers are encouraged to write to Sony.
      6. Lavender Health: Animated PSA about Hepatitis B and HIV. Joyce Dunmore is interviewed.
      7. Lambda Update: William A. Peters introduces the broadcast. Beatrice Dohrn speaks about Daniel Miller, a man in Pensylvania fired from his job because he was gay.
      8. Wigstock 93 footage. Runs over the end credits as well.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 35 [Air date: 9/1/1994], September 1994; ID: 231.0417 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0417)
      1. News Notes: Two TV specials on Martina Navertalova, who was just named as president of Women's Tennis Association. Rumor is that Gay Games is $1 million in debt. NY Times on Provincetown vacations. Giuliani still trying to gut AIDS Services. Tokyo hosts Pride March. Gay group marches in parallel with India Day parade. Four high school football stars are arrested in Texas over murder of a gay man. Nebraska lesbian wins custody of son. A Mississippi ambulance service leaves an AIDS patient to die on his porch; he didn't die and is now suing. Humm's mic keeps spiking during this segment.
      2. David Blanton, a new correspondent on GCN, is introduced. Blanton works for Vote Smart, and introduces the organization. Adelaide B. Elm of Vote Smart is interviewed over the phone.
      3. Steve Weinstein interviews photographer Carolyn Jones and Michael Liberatore, author of Living Proof: Courage in the Face of AIDS. A clip from Living Proof: HIV and the Pursuit of Happiness is shown.
      4. Damien Corboy, a former senate aide, is interviewed about the chances of a Democratic takeover of the house and senate.
      5. GLAAD Media Alert: Lifetime presents 1-hour biography of Martina Navertalova, making only a brief, matter-of-fact statement on her lesbianism. Viewers are encouraged to write to Lifetime.
      6. Dale Hogan reviews The Adventures of Priscilla: Queen of the Desert. A clip is shown.
      7. Lavender Health: Torrence Allen and D'Jeno Jean Romain are interviewed.
      8. Lady Bunny, organizer of Wigstock is interviewed.
      9. Lengthy outro from Humm and Sharmatt followed by another clip from Priscilla.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 36 [Air date: 9/8/1994], September 1994; ID: 231.0418 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0418)
      1. News Notes: The New York Times runs an article that 1 in 5 people have had a homosexual attraction at some point in their life. Another NY Times article about gays saving inner cities. The death of Michael Peters and Walter Raine are announced. A man who believed AIDS could be passed through sneezing set out to murder Governer Cumo and slit the throat of Francis Tarlton. Dr. Tusch, who ran Laser Medical Associates (advertised heavily on GCN), and had 49 malpractice counts against him, attempted suicide and relocated to Washington state. His medical license was never revoked. Dan Quayle considers running for president.
      2. Karen Burstein, candidate for Attorney General is interviewed.
      3. Tom Duane is interviewed.
      4. At Wigstock, Lou Maletta interviews Ruth Messinger about the upcoming primaries.
      5. GLAAD Media Alert: Andre Agassi makes homophobic statements, Nike continues to sponsor him. Viewers are encouraged to call Nike and demand Agassi either be removed or made to apologize.
      6. Lavender Health: Coverage of the 12th Annual American Association of Physicians for Human Rights conference. Jane Petro and Bob Cabaj of AAPHR, and a medical student named Clarissa Kripke are interviewed. Kate O'Hanlan speaks.
      7. Damien Corboy is interviewed about the House of Representatives.
      8. The Lambda Update: Gay and lesbian adoption is covered. Beatrice Dohrn is interviewed.
      9. Wigstock 94 is covered.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 37 [Air date: 9/15/1994], September 1994; ID: 231.0419 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0419)
      1. GCN's Coverage of the 1994 Primaries. Lee Sharmat and Damien Corby report. Mario Cuomo speaks and is interviewed about the gay and lesbian civil rights bill. The Attorney General race is covered from Karen Burstein's HQ. Burstein makes a speech. Catherine Aboti, newly elected state senator, is interviewed. Tom Duane speaks after losing his congressional run. Chris Quinn, campaign manager, political analyst Bob Bailey, and Jerry Nadler are interviewed.
      2. News Notes: 60 Minutes interviews Bob McFarlane, former advisor to Reagan, who calls Oliver North a 'degenerate liar'. Shannon Faulkner, student at The Citadel, is covered. African-American women 15 times more likely to have AIDS than white women. Gay students are being assaulted in Washington state schools and few reports have been filed because the abuse is so routine for gay and lesbian students. Forced HIV testing being considered in Russia. OJ Simpson gossip. OutLoud is announced. California governor Pete Wilson vetoes domestic partners law. Humm and Sharmat discuss Priscilla: Queen of the Desert.